So let's run through
the measurement system right
now. I'm going to
teach you how to
interpret some of the
data so you can
learn a lesson. All
right, so step one.
When you plan this
video, you chose a
primary goal, views, sales,
or emails, and that's
all you're measuring it
against now. So don't
try to evaluate every
metric at once. Just
stick to the one
goal you set at
the start unless you're
black belt. So if
your goal was views,
that's what we're going
to judge for. If
your goal was email
signups, that's what we're
going to look at.
If your goal was
sales, we're only going
to really care about
that. Step two is
to do a three
-hour check. So on
the three -hour mark,
come and look at
your video. Don't change
anything before this because
YouTube's still collecting data
and making changes too
soon. It's going to
add stress and confusion
and time -wasting. And
then once you've hit
the three -hour check,
look where your video
ranks on your one
to 10 board. And
if it's in your
top four and matches
or beats your expectations,
just leave it. If
it has momentum, let
it run. If it's
sitting at five or
six, that's the middle.
And that's what you
expected. Don't touch it.
That's still a win.
If it's a seven
to 10 and that's
below what you expected,
then maybe test a
new thumbnail or title.
Now, if your thumbnail
split tester has loaded
at this point, which
is unlikely unless you
are a larger channel
and no option is
clearly winning by 6
% or more, go
ahead and set it.
If the difference is
small or you don't
have enough data yet,
leave it and come
back in 24 hours
or so. But keep
this in mind. At
this point, your video
has only really been
shown to fans and
return viewers. It's not
really representing the wider
market. Now, whilst you're
there, you can hop
on over to RevTrack
to check the business
performance. But what I
would say is at
this early stage, it's
likely to have had
game -changing results. And
also just keep in
mind that sometimes a
video is going to
look like a views
flop. If you're very
small or new, you're
not going to have
much data here. Okay,
then the next step
is you come back
on the 24 -hour
mark. And by now,
YouTube's had more time
to test your video
with different audience types,
especially returning viewers. So
you're going to have
more data. It's still
going to be early,
but now we can
start to make smarter
calls. If your video
is ranking in the
top four and it
matches or beats your
expectations, don't make any
changes. It's likely got
some momentum. And if
that continues, it can
keep growing steadily for
weeks. If your video
is sitting at five
or 10, it's the
middle still, that's solid.
If you expected a
breakout and it's not
quite there, sure, you
could tweak the thumbnail
and title again. But
most of the time,
it's probably better just
to leave it and
learn the lesson. And
if it's ranking seven
to 10 and it's
clearly underperforming and way
off your expectations based
on the ones that
we set from my
chart, this is the
moment to take an
action by changing the
title or the thumbnail.
If you want. For
me, I'll change the
title first, but usually
I just go, ah,
I'll write that one
off. What's the lesson?
Because that's the most
important thing rather than
spending hours saving it.
And then in the
24 hour mark, go
and look at your
business data too. If
your video is underperforming
for views, but crushing
it for emails, link
clicks or sales, that's
not a loss. That's
a sign we can
learn from. Remember, don't
let emotion override you
here. Everything in test.
Nobody's going to die
from this. And then
the next step is
we do the seven
day check. So at
this point, YouTube's finished
its initial rounds of
testing. And you're going
to have a much
clearer picture of how
the video landed with
your audience and whether
it has real momentum
or not. So here's
how we think about
it. If your video
is still ranking the
top four, congratulations, that's
a strong performer. That
doesn't mean it's going
to go viral, but
it does mean it's
gained traction. And what
we want to do
is we want to
ask, what worked here?
Why did this do
well? That's the question
you'll start answering in
the next lesson. But
for now, flag it
as a video worth
repeating in some way.
If your video sits
at a five or
six, it's doing exactly
what we want it
to. It's doing exactly
to do. It's middle
performing. So it's steadily
growing your channel. Again,
you can learn from
it or just move
on and aim to
replace another middle video
next time. And then
if your video is
sitting in the seven
out of 10 range,
we don't try to
save it now. We
just go, why did
that happen? What can
we learn? Because unless
there is an obvious
fundamental title fix, the
best thing you can
do is just walk
away and apply the
lesson to the next
video. And don't forget
a seven out of
10 for views might
still be a one
out of 10 for
sales or leads. And
that's when we go
over to our RevTrack
dashboard. And this is
the important business stage.
What we want to
be doing now is
going, did it drive
link clicks? Did it
bring in emails? Did
it generate revenue? Did
it get calls? If
the answer is yes,
ignore the view count.
We're not here to
win a popularity contest.
We're building a business.
So we need to
ask why. Now below
this video, you'll see
there's another one about
how to use RevTrack.
And that's a step
-by -step tutorial for
anyone with the software
can follow. And then
there's one more check
we can do on
the 30 day mark.
Most creators never look
at this because they're
so blinded by the
performance of the one
out of 10 board.
They forget about any
video that isn't on
it. But if you
do that, you're not
going to spot pattern.
A more long -term.
So here's what we
want to do on
the 30 day mark.
We want to be
looking at, how is
the video doing? Is
it still bringing in
steady views at day
30? If it is,
it means YouTube slowly
pushing it out to
new people. And that's
a strong sign of
an evergreen video. So
at this point, you
want to check the
thumbnail and title. If
it's working, don't touch
it. You want to
look at the format.
Is it a process,
a listicle, or a
deep dive and repeat
it again? You want
to look at the
business performance. Did it
grow the business more
than other videos? And
if so, point more
videos at it. Now,
some videos are going
to flatline by day
30. That's totally normal.
But the ones that
keep going, those are
gold. Because if you
can build a few
strong evergreen videos that
keep pulling in views,
you start stacking traffic
and the system gets
easier. So don't just
measure performance in the
first few days. Use
the 30 day mark
to spot your slow
burners too. These are
the videos that can
really grow the business
well. Now, this might
feel like a heck
of a lot, but
don't worry. You don't
need to follow all
of these steps at
the exact time. Otherwise,
this doesn't work. If
you can't make the
three hour mark, do
it at the six.
Or if you can't
make it at all,
just come back the
next day. The truth
is, all we're really
doing here is trying
to learn one lesson
per video. Some videos
might teach you 10.
Others, it might be
hard to find one.
So all you do
is look, learn a
lesson. Is it above
expectations? If so, repeat
that lesson. Is it
below? Learn why. And
then point anything back
at anything that's growing
the business in the
way that you'd hoped.
Like, it's not more
complex than that. Now,
sometimes you think you
will have learned a
lesson and you're going
to action it in
the next video and
it won't work. But
don't worry, this doesn't
mean you're wrong. You
have to try the
lesson multiple times before
you write it off.
And then all you
do is just use
the spreadsheet I've got
you here and you
mark down the results
of each stage and
then you write your
lesson. So I would
paste in your video
link, put the date,
select the dropdown as
to the format that
it is, put the
views in each of
them and the sales
data. And then you've
got this bird's eye
view. You can really
quickly look and go,
oh, look, short process
is my best style.
Do more of that.
Or look, oh, that
title is really good.
Do more of that.
Now, RevTrack users, you
are going to have
click, sales, email, call
data all in one
place. You can still
make this sheet if
you want because RevTrack
won't track like the
three hour data in
the same way. But
really the only thing
out of all of
this is just we
learn one lesson per
video and repeat it.
So move on to
the next video where
I'm going to show
you how to learn
lessons.